(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T13:28:55.293135",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
さあ 睡眠打破 昼夜逆転 VOX AC30W
So, it's time to wake up, turn the VOX AC30W up
テレキャスター背負った バンド仲間にゃやっほー
A Telecaster worn by a suburban boy
アルバイトはネモモード
Working part-time is so emo,
対バンにはATフィールド
And the AT field crushes his ego,
人見知り宣言で逃げる気か boy
Running away with an antisocial declaration, boy.
ゆーてお坊ちゃんお嬢ちゃん
Hey there, arrogant little brat,
お前も才能もなまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
Money, talent, you've got them all, but you're just a nuisance!
Boys be ambitious like this old man
長い前髪 君誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
勘違いすんなよ 教祖はおめえだ
You're mistaken, the guru is you!
ロキロキのロックンロール かき鳴らすレイヴ
Rockin' rockin' roll, rockin' rockin' roll, strum it out!
ドインストップ ドインストップ
Don't stop, don't stop!
さあ君の全てを 暴き出してみせろよ
Show me everything you've got!
ロキロキのロックンロール
Rockin' rockin' roll, rockin' rockin' roll!
さあ 日進月歩
So, take a step up!
いい曲書いてる 動員増えてる
New song in the brew, is it buzzing too?
「知名度あるけど 人気はそんなにないから 色々大変ですね」
"Your name is known, but your fame is lame, so I feel really bad for you."
はっきり言うなよ 匿名アイコン
Say it clearly, anonymous icon!
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
Show your real face, profile icon!
いい気こいて自意識まだ boy
Acting all wise, feeling self-important, boy.
賢くあざとくやったって 10年後にメークは落ちてんだよ
No matter how clever you try to be, in ten years, your colors will show.
Boys be ambitious like this old man
生き抜くためだ メイク take a selfie selfie selfie
It's on the line, take a selfie, selfie, selfie!
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにさ
We'll make it through, each and every one of us!
ロキロキのロックンロール
Rockin' rockin' roll, rockin' rockin' roll!
お上品にしがみついて満足できない?
Blinded by perfection, but can't get no satisfaction!
奢侈に溺れてくすぶるどこどこここは
All these pricey goods and gizmos trying to seduce me!
足元あしぶら シンプルプレッシャーで一杯
Sanity, sanity, the pressure is crushing!
実は昨日から買って声が出ません
"Hate to break the news, but my voice died, the show is off tonight."
はあ? はあ? はあ? はあ?
Huh? Say what? No way! Shut up!
寝言は寝て言えベイビー
Keep dreaming with your wisecracks, baby!
生き残るためだけ決めろテカ セルフィー
I'll see you on the other side, if only we survive!
信じらんねえぞ お互いにさ
Rockin' rockin' roll, rockin' rockin' roll!
ロキロキのロックンロール
Make love with your electric guitar!
ロックンロールすべらないラストソングでもいいドンストップドンストップ
Oh baby, don't stop, don't stop!
プライドのないなら中身のいって見せろよ
So, are you giving up? Better show me what you've got!
ロキロキのロックンロール
Oh baby, rockin' rockin' roll, rockin' rockin' roll!
お互いにさ
I'll see you on the other side!
ロキロキのロックンロール
Get ready for a rocky ride!
ロックンロール
We'll rock n' roll until we die!
ベイビーベイビーベイビー
Better make it through alive!
死ぬんじゃねーぞ お互いにさ
Don't you dare die on me, both of us.
ルキルキのロックロックロキ
Roki roki rock rock roki
気付けば電撃釘付けさ
Before we knew it, electrified and glued.
どうすんだ どうすんだ
What do we do? What do we do?
先のすべてを剥ぎ出しに見せろや
Show me all of the future stripped bare!
ルキルキのロックロックロキ
Roki roki rock rock roki
死ぬんじゃねーぞ お互いにさ
Don't you dare die on me, both of us.
死に高嶺の華 お互いさま
A dead flower on a high peak, we're the same.
何をしても不器用で
I'm so clumsy in everything that I do,
何かとミスばっか
things go wrong cause I make mistakes.
ダメダメな私だって
I feel like I'm so useless,
できることがあるの
but there is something I can do.
凹んで悲しくたって
When you are feeling blue and sad,
笑顔にしてあげるんだ
I can always make you smile.
ここにいるから 早く
I am waiting for you here,
私を見つけてね
so find me soon!
Love you love you. I love you.
Love you love you. I love you so much.
Love you love you. 愛してもっと
Love you love you. Need you to love me more.
いつでも隣りにいるし
I'll be with you every time you need me,
いつでも一緒に笑える
and we'll always laugh together.
私をたくさん知って
I want you to know more about me,
たくさん好きって言って
and tell me you love me so much.
ワガママで朝も苦手
Not a morning person and so selfish,
ドジだしダメダメだけど
I am all thumbs and good for nothing.
それでも私のことを見ててね
Will you still love me the way I am?
描く夢の未来へ続く
The way to the future of our dreams,
道をキミと歩けますように
I wish I could walk it hand in hand with you.
ねぇ もっと! 好きになってもらいたいのに
Hey baby, I really want you to love me!
頭の中は君ばっか!!
I cannot stop thinking about you!
ってゆーかそっけないなんて向いてないで!
Look me in the eyes, don't go away!
あぁもう! ヤキモキしちゃうわ あぁ
I get into a stew, oh no!
あぁ ずっとずっと好きがいいの!
Want you to love me, love me forever!
心の奥もときめいてしまうくらいにこっち向いててよねだり
Fell in love with you so my heart is beating fast,
あぁもう離さないから、絶対に!
I will never let you go forever!
Love you love you. I love you.
Love you love you. I love you so much.
Love you love you. 愛してもっと
Love you love you. Need you to love me more.
キミがいるから 私
I can do my best because I have you,
いつでも頑張れるんだ
you're the reason I'm not afraid.
凹んで悲しくたって キミがいるから...
When I am feeling blue and sad...
キミがいるから歩いてこれた
I could take a step forward because of you,
キミがなくちゃ 前も見れない
can't even see anything without you.
嫌なこととか辛いこととかあったって キミの力でここまで笑ってこられたんだ
I could get over hard times because you made me happy.
今度はもっと私がぐっと引っ張って 連れて行くんだ
I am gonna lead you and take you to the place.
キミがいるから 私がいるの こんな私を 愛してしてくれる?
You're why I live, will you love someone like me?
ねぇ もっと ねぇ もっと まだもっと 受け止めてよね! ねぇいい? さあ声を上げて!
Hey baby, I need you, I will give you all my love!
ねぇ もっと ねぇ もっと 好きになってもらいたいのお
Hey baby, I really want you to love me more!
いつでもそう 私ばっかりみたいにそっぽなんて向かせないわ
I will never let you turn away from me.
ねぇほら夢中にしちゃうわ あぁ ずっとずっと好きがいいの!
I will drive you crazy, want you to love me forever!
心も体も染まっちゃうくらいにこっち向いててよねだり
Will you love me with all your heart and soul?
ふたり もう離さないから
We'll never be apart again,
絶対に 絶対ね 絶対よ 約束だよ
I promise you, absolutely, forever.
愛しちゃう もっと
I want to love you even more!
暗い方ばっか見てないで ウラッパッパッパパラリラ踊れよ
Don't just look at the dark side, dance to the rhythm!
魔界学校の優等生 華やかな我が魔力讃えよ
An honor student of demon school, praise my splendid magic!
イナイイナイばぁでこっち向いて 仄かな未来を咲かせよ
Peekaboo, look this way, and let a faint future bloom!
次第相関保って高まって溜まったMP放て黒魔術
Keep the connection, build up your MP, and release black magic!
定の刻に集え闇に奮えケルベロス
Gather at the appointed hour, tremble in the darkness, Cerberus!
切に響く言葉はブチ切れハッピーパラダイス
The words echoing earnestly are a furiously happy paradise!
キラリ心奥底まで届け これからも私の元で
Sparkle deep into my heart, stay by my side from now on!
不思議な力打ち放して 世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Unleash this mysterious power and make the whole world smile!
ウラッパッパッパパラリラ歌えば 一緒一緒だよ
Sing along to the rhythm, we'll be together forever!
暗いも落度してないで 生まれた身体さらば踊れよ
Don't dwell on the gloom, bare your born body and dance!
視界外目逸らさないで 今はただ離れてかないで
Don't look away from my sight, just don't leave me right now!
いやーんいやーん待ってあっち向いて 今はまだ心の準備を
No way, wait, look over there, my heart isn't ready yet!
期待遮って固まって パタパタパタパタパラリラ放て黒魔術
Block the expectations and freeze, fluttering black magic!
呪文の如く夜に震え震えるベロス 切に響く言葉は
Trembling in the night like a spell, the words echoing earnestly
ぶち切れハッピーパラダイス
are a furiously happy paradise!
我れに続け今宵よ 闇を破れネメシアよ
Follow me tonight, shatter the darkness, Nemesia!
朽つべきものその名は 眠りの羽床パラダイス
What must perish, its name is the resting-feather paradise!
キラリ心奥底まで届け 白黒つけてあげるから
Sparkle deep into our hearts, since I'll settle it for you!
不思議な力振りかざして みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
Brandish this mysterious power and make everyone smile!
ウラッパッパッパパラリラ歌えば 一緒一緒だよ
Sing along to the rhythm, we'll be together forever!
キラリヒラリと紫に染まって これからもあなたの元で
Shimmering and fluttering in purple, staying by your side always
奇跡の呪文とき放て 咲かせる笑顔の花を
Release the spell of miracles and make the flowers of smile bloom!
キラリ心奥底まで届け これからも変わらないままで
Sparkle deep into my heart, staying unchanged from now on
不思議な力ほら宿って 世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Behold, mysterious power dwells, making the world smile too!
ウラッパッパッパパラリラ歌えば 一緒一緒だよ 絶対一緒だよ
Sing along to the rhythm, we'll be together forever, absolutely together forever!
あー良かったよ！
Ah, that was great!
よかった！一緒に歌えてね
Yay! We got to sing together!
一緒一緒に歌えて...可愛かったよ、あくたん
Singing together... you were so cute, Akutan!
私たちさ、今日アイドルだね。そうだよ！
We're idols today, aren't we? That's right!
私たち今日芸人じゃないんだよ。今日アイドルだよ！
We're not comedians today. We're idols today!
みんなな、見えてるか？見えてる！ ということで皆さんどうも、こんあくあ、みなさんあくあんで
Can you guys see us? Yes, we can! So everyone, hello, Kon-akua, everyone it's Akuan—
そして、はい、こんばんは、紫シオンです。どうも！あくしおです。ということで
And, hi, good evening, it's Murasaki Shion. Hello! We're Akushio. So—
今日はあくしお3Dライブということで、はい、どうですか？どうですか？
Today is the Akushio 3D Live, so, um, how is it? How is it?
お気持ちは？いやいいですね、最初ろきからこれこれね、これから始まって、いや来たね、寂しくないんじゃないか
How are you feeling? Well, it's great, starting right from the start like this... Oh, it's here, aren't you lonely—
あ、紫色パレット！
Ah, purple palette!
えっ？
Eh?
色々、えっと待って待って待って。
Wait, wait, wait, hold on...
私のオリジナル曲だよねそれ。あれ？
That's my original song, right? Huh?
紫色パレット歌って、ねえじょうぶばれっ…
Singing "Purple Palette," hey, Jōbu Bar-...
えっちょっ…そしたら、じょうぶあくあパレットにならなきゃいけないずっとも思うんだけど。
Wait, hold on... Then wouldn't it have to be "Jōbu Aqua Palette"?
あれ？
Huh?
おかしいねこれ。
That's weird.
あ、入ってきちゃった！おかしい！
Ah, it kicked in! Weird!
おかしい！おかしいねこれ。
Weird! That's so weird!
はい、ということでね、みんなどうだったかな？
So, everyone, how was it?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みんな笑ってるね、「くさ」って言ってる。
Everyone's laughing, saying "Kusa."
おい! アイドルに向かって「くさ」って！
Hey! Calling an idol "kusa"?!
そうだよ、今日はあ、アイドルだから…え？
That's right, today I'm... an idol, so—eh?
え、可愛い？私たちアクシオちゃんだからね！アクシオ、アクシオちゃんなのよ。
Eh, cute? We're AquaShio, you know! AquaShio, we're AquaShio!
マジで意味かんないけど。
I seriously don't get what that means.
え、可愛いしょ？今日のサムネ、超気に入ってんだからね！可愛いしょ？アクシオちゃん！アクシオちゃんなのよ！
Eh, cute right? I really love today's thumbnail! Cute, right? AquaShio! AquaShio!
ダイソンで…
With Dyson…
え、ちょっと！ねえ待って！ちょっと…
Eh, wait! Hey, wait! Hold on...
ねえ、やだ！ネコ耳占いないで！私たちのチャンネルのホビ…
Hey, no! Don't predict cat ears! Our channel's Hobi—
紫シオ、ホビ占い！
Murasaki Shio, Hobi fortune-telling!
ホビ占い！占い！で、今日はね…
Hobi fortune-telling! Fortune! So today…
あ、の、最後にね、なんかすごい告知が…ある！
Ah, um, at the very end, there's, like, an amazing announcement…!
あ！ね？そう、あるから、とも、お楽しみにしていてくれたら嬉しいです！
Ah! Right? There is, so please look forward to it!
じゃ、ちょっと、もう次の曲、まだありますから。
Well, um, we still have more songs coming up.
そうですね、次曲行く？
That's right, shall we go to the next song?
こっからは2人ですかね？2人で歌う？そうだよ、2人で歌うんだよ。
From here on, it's just the two of us? Singing together? That's right, we're singing together.
歌うか、じゃあ。
Shall we sing, then?
じゃ、じゃあじゃない、そうだよ、下に飛ぶんだよ今日は。
Not "then," yeah, that's right, we're jumping down today.
やっぱアクシオライブ…そうだよ、歌うこっ…アクシオちゃんでよ、アクシオちゃんとして…飛ぼっか、じゃあ。
As expected from an AquaShio live… That's right, singing… as AquaShio… Let's jump, then.
じゃあ、その前にちょっとお着替えを…
Well, before that, let's change clothes a bit…
あ、そうそうそう！ちょっと見ないでよ。
Ah, that's right, that's right! Don't look, okay?
そうだよ、見ないでよ、みんな！ちょっと見ないでよ！変態待ち望んで、見たいんでしょ本当は！見たいなら…しょうがないでしょ、しょうがないのが壁側にいるから。
That's right, don't look, everyone! Don't look! You've been waiting for perverts, you actually want to see! If you want to see… it can't be helped, since the pervert is against the wall.
だから、あとでね！あとでね、バーイバーイ！
So, later! Later, bye-bye!
劣等上等 Bring it on
Bring It On
列島上等 不眠日和
Archipelago Superior, sleepless weather
子ども騙しのマゼマゼチカ
Childish parlor tricks mixed together
ご立派 警鐘 気取りで
Putting on a noble, alarmist act
高みの見物ばかりじゃつまんねえ
Just watching from the sidelines is so boring
ほらもっと 間違って上等
Come on, more mistakes are welcome!
退屈に手をかけて
Reaching out to boredom
こんなところじゃ終われない
We can't end in a place like this
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm I'm losing my mind
ごっご遊びも芝居もさようなら
Say goodbye to playing pretend and acting
ずっとこのままなんてさ irarenai yo
We can't stay like this forever
ダッダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da-da, I'm becoming an adult
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting both the sour and the sweet right now
パッパッパッパ 変わる時代
Pa-pa-pa-pa, the times are changing
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょ
It can't be all bad, right?
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
Past, sins, punishment, all of it
素手で、愛で、生き抜いてやり返すわ
Surviving barehanded, with love, and fighting back!
yeah, chou hatsu atashitachi wa no doubt
Yeah, ultra-provocative, we are no doubt
緑のアイツにばっかり matten ne
Always waiting on that green one, huh?
さあburn up いつになったら貰える合格
Now burn up, when will I finally get a passing grade?
赤ペンいれてよどこがダメなんですか
Mark it with a red pen, what's wrong with it anyway?
酒女金ドラック やっちゃってコンプラ
Booze, women, money, drugs, breaking all the compliance
チルってaiight... 冗談じゃんブラックジョーク
Chilling is aight... just kidding, it's a black joke
中指立てたくなるような事情
There are so many reasons to stick up my middle finger
ありすぎて指が足りねえから hands up
Too many to count, so put your hands up!
and what's up saitei? moto moto daro bring it on
And what's up, loser? It was always like this, bring it on
"まあまあ" なんかいらない 欲しがりまし死ぬまでは
We don't need "there, there," wanting it until I die
伸びた背丈そうだった街に投げキス
Blowing a kiss to the city where I grew up tall
見せばわっから覚悟しとけよ
Showtime's starting, so you better be prepared!
ダッダッダ 僕ら大人になる
Da-da-da, we're becoming adults
カウンター狙い冴えない日々に
Aiming for a counterattack in dull days
淡々とカマス一撃劇
Calmly pulling off a single striking blow
誰も読めない先未だあいこでしょ
The future is unreadable, still a tie, right?
バグも ロスも ズレも すべて
Bugs, losses, misalignments, all of it
素手で 生きて！ 生き抜いて靴ガエスヨ
Living barehanded! Surviving and turning the tables!
ダッダッダ クダラナイ
Da-da-da, meaningless
コトバッカガ ユズルナイ
Things I'll never yield on
ワカルカ？ アタシノビガク
Do you understand? My aesthetics
コノバカショウジキナ
This foolishly honest
コブシヒトツガ
Single fist is
(イチスンデンス)
(a matter of an inch)
キリフダ
My trump card
(クチョクナンデンス)
(pure-hearted stubbornness)
ガナルレットウ
Roaring inferiority
イチヌケヨ
Drop out first!
サラバ！
Farewell!
コンナモンジャナイ
This isn't all there is
ダッダッダッダ あたし大人になる
Da-da-da-da, I'm becoming an adult
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting both the sour and the sweet right now
燦々 交わるミライ
Brilliantly intersecting futures
もう子どもじゃないのわかるでしょ
You know we're not kids anymore, right?
時代 機会 待ってくれない
Times and opportunities won't wait for us
素手で、捨て身で、生き抜いて上等だわ
Barehanded, desperate, surviving is top-tier!
愛ある時代
An era filled with love
それでは皆様お先にバイ、ガイズ！
Well then, ladies and gentlemen, bye guys!
こんなんじゃまだ足りない
This isn't enough yet.
あたし大人になる
I'm becoming an adult.
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting the sweet and sour now,
燦々交わるミライ
our futures brightly intersect.
もう子供じゃないのわかるでしょ
You know I'm no longer a child, right?
時代 機械 待ってくれない
Times and machines won't wait for us.
素手で 捨て身で 生き抜いて上等だわ
Barehanded, desperate, surviving with pride!
それでは皆さん先にバイバイ
Well then, everyone, bye-bye first!
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない
I won't let a romance scandal get away,
決してあげない
I'll never let you off!
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら
Oath! When I become president...
Oath! When I become president,
人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします
I'll exile any woman who flirts with taken men!
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら
Oath! When I become president,
「いや、ただの友達だよ~」って誤魔化す奴はヘソから電流を流します
I'll electrocute anyone who says, "No, we're just friends!"
だ・だ・だ・大胆不敵 セーショナルクローズアップ
D-d-d-da fearless, sensational close-up!
D,D,D,Don't cry やるぜ徹底的にリサーチだ
D-d-d-don't cry, I'll thoroughly research this!
大嫌い? しょうがない? クズは病気ね バイバイ・バイ
Hate it? No choice? Scum's a disease, bye-bye!
権力! 財産! 地位名誉!!
Power! Property! Status, prestige!
なんにもないけど裁きたいでしょ?
You want to judge me over nothing, don't you?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね
D-d-d-da once I become president,
まずは君を捕まえるね
I'll catch you first.
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせるね
With a wet towel, I'll make you confess!
宣誓! 私が大統領になったら
Oath! When I become president,
ただの仕事の付き合いだよ~って言う奴は二度と働けなくしてやります
I'll make sure business associates never work again!
宣誓! 以下略!
Oath! The rest is abbreviated!
いや向こうが強引さ~っていう男の口にはレジンを流し込んで固めてやります!
I'll pour resin in the mouth of any guy who was pushy!
み・み・み・密着 まさしくドン・ファン気取りスキャンダラス
Close, close, close! Don Juan-like, scandalous!
ま・ま・ま・末端価格 甲斐性なしのスコープね
Low-end price, a scope with no backbone!
愛はない? 理由じゃない 悪くないのねはいはいはい
No love? That's not the reason, yes, yes, yes!
軽薄! のうのう! いけしゃあしゃあ!!
Frivolous! Shameless! How audacious!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になってもね
D-d-d-da even if I become president,
多分君は変わらないね シャラッととぼけて
You probably won't change, playing it cool.
ですか こんばんは
Is that so? Good evening.
本気ですか そうですか
Are you serious? Is that so?
情熱とは不注意 微熱も消してしまいたい
Passion is carelessness; I'd like to extinguish even a fever.
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね
D-d-d-da once I become president,
マジで君を捕まえるね
I'll catch you for real.
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせるね
With a wet towel, I'll make you confess!
どこですか 今あんた 見っけちゃった バれちゃった
Where are you? I spotted you, you've been caught!
夜道には御用心 代わりに銃声 シル・ヴ・プレ・プレジデント
Beware of the night, gunshots instead, president!
ああ、お粥今日もかっこいいなー
Ah, Okayu is so cool today too!
お粥明日結婚しようねー
Okayu, let's get married tomorrow!
はあ? お粥は私と明日結婚するんだけど
Huh? Okayu is marrying me tomorrow!
え? 私のお粥だけど
Eh? But Okayu is mine!
いや、お粥と明日結婚するけどね? え?
Well, Okayu and I are getting married tomorrow, you know? Eh?
待ってよ、お粥は私と結婚するんだよ!
Wait, Okayu is marrying me!
え? 結婚しようって言ってないでしょ?
Eh? You never said you'd marry her!
いや、言ったよ! でもだって明日結婚するって、お粥言ってたもん!
I did! Okayu said we're getting married tomorrow!
え、それ何回言われてるの? だっだって「もう結婚する」って言われてもう2年近く言われてまだ結婚してないじゃん!
For almost two years she's been saying "we're getting married" and you still aren't!
そんなことないよ! ディープキスとか言って...もう結婚してるもん!
That's not true! She talked about deep kissing... we're already married!
もう結婚してるがちで!
We're totally married for real!
さあ、約束ずっとしておいて、結婚また今度ね、また今度ねって引き延ばすて...
You keep making promises, saying "Let's get married next time," and dragging it out...
まだかわいい！
It's still cute!
そんな、そんな、あんた1回も言ったことないくせにさ、
Come on, you've never even said that once,
お前とさ、結婚するなんてさ、
and saying you'd marry me, like...
まだ待ってくれてんの、やっぱりさ、
You're still waiting for me, after all,
まだんだよ、考えが、
you've still got a long way to go in your thinking,
ほんなのもよんの、こんなの、
and look at this, what is this?
なんで、負けねえぞ、お前よ、お前との愛は、私のが強いから！
Why—I won't lose! Because my love for you is stronger!
私がチューリングラブ歌ってんの！
I'm the one singing "Turing Love"!
いやいっぱいコラボしてます！私だってコラボしか、こんなこと、こんなこと、
No, we've collaborated tons! I've only collaborated... such things...
一体なあ、あれ？
What on earth... Huh?
ここどこ？あれ？
Where is this? Huh?
はいったあ！
I got in!
あれ？
Huh?
私じゃない。
It's not me.
ここどこ？私じゃない。
Where is this? It's not me.
かゆっ、ちょ、ケツかゆっ。
It itchy— wait, my butt is itchy.
お、私？ケツかゆっ。
Oh, me? My butt's itchy.
私、ケツかゆくない、おし、お、あれ？腹んかゆっ。
My butt isn't itchy, wait, oh, huh? My stomach is itchy.
もしかしてしおんちゃんこれ？
Could this be Shion-chan?
ちょっとすみません！
Excuse me, please!
お、ケツかゆっ。
My butt's itchy.
私、それ私ですけど、
That's me, though...
なに？えっ？なになに？はい、誰ですか？
What? Eh? What's this? Yes, who are you?
私誰なんでしょう？みなとあくあです。
Who am I? I'm Minato Aqua.
あなた誰ですか？私...
Who are you? I...
私？
Me?
私メイドの仕事...紫咲しおんさんですよね、あなた。え？あなたですよね、紫咲しおんさん。
My maid job... You're Murasaki Shion-san, right? Eh? You're Murasaki Shion-san, right?
あなた誰ですか？
Who are you?
あとしお、あとしお、あとしお...
Atishio, Atishio, Atishio...
あとしお誰ですか？パーフェクトメイド！パーフェクト...
Who is Atishio? Perfect maid! Perfect...
料理も掃除も大好き、ううん、だいすき、ううん、違うね、違うね。
Loves cooking and cleaning too— no, loves it, no, that's wrong, that's wrong.
あなたは紫咲しおんさん、私みなとあく...もしかしてあなた...
You are Murasaki Shion-san, I am Minato Aqua... could it be you...
はい。みなとあくあさんですか？
Yes. Are you Minato Aqua-san?
はい、みんな、さっきから、そう、も3回目よ、3回目よ。
Yes, everyone, from earlier, like, this is the 3rd time, the 3rd time.
ってことは、私よ。ってことは？ってことはあなた誰？
That means it's me. That means? That means who are you?
あとしおん！
Atishion!
で、この、このすごいざっくり言うと
And, to put it very broadly,
うわあ！
Wow!
あとしおん、あとしおんちょっと気付かなかった。
Atishion, Atishion didn't notice for a bit.
あれ？私パーフェクトメイドだからお仕事して...
Huh? I'm a perfect maid so I work...
違うよね！違うから仕事はねしないから。そう。
That's wrong! That's wrong, so I don't work. Yeah.
もうゲーム、ゲームしてんの、ゲームしてんの、ニート、ニート、あとしおニート！
You're just gaming, gaming, NEET, NEET, Atishion is a NEET!
あとしおニート、あとしおニート、メイド、メイド、メイド！
Atishion is a NEET, maid, maid, maid!
ニート、違うの、の、の、メイド、メイド、メイド、色々おかしくなっちゃうからね、これ。うん、あれは、うん。
NEET, no, no, no, maid, maid, maid, things are getting weird because of this. Yeah, that's, yeah.
始まれ！
Start!
まだこの世界は 僕を飼い馴らしていたみたいだ
It seems like this world's still trying to tame me,
望み通りいいだろう 美しくもがくよ
if that's the way, I will obey, beautifully struggling.
互いの砂時計 眺めながらキスをしようよ
While seeing both of our hourglasses, let's share a kiss.
「さよなら」から一番 遠い 場所で待ち合わせよう
Let's make a plan to meet somewhere most far from "goodbye".
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を伸ばしても届かない
Words like "destiny" or "future"—no matter how far they extend their hands,
場所で僕ら恋をする
they won't reach the place where we fall in love.
時計の針も二人を横目に見ながら進む そんな世界を二人で一生 いや、何章でも 生き抜いていこう
Even the hands of the clock look at us sideways as they tick. Let's live through a world like this together, for a lifetime—no, for as many chapters as it takes.
「はじめまして」なんてさ 遥か彼方へと追いやって
Pushing "nice to meet you" far, far away,
1000年周期を 一日で息しよう
let's breathe a thousand-year cycle in a single day.
辞書にある言葉で作れ上がった世界を憎んだ 万華鏡の中で八月の朝
I hated a world made of dictionary words. Inside a kaleidoscope on an August morning,
君は僕の前で はにかんでみせすました
you stood in front of me and acted shy.
この世界の教科書のような笑顔で 嘘みたいな日々を 規格外の意味を 悲劇だっていいから望んだ
With a smile like the textbook of this world, I wished for days like a lie, for extraordinary meaning, even if it's a tragedy.
まだこの世界は
Seems like the world's still
僕を飼いならしてたみたいだ
trying to tame me,
望み通りいいだろう
If that's what you want, alright,
美しくもがくよ
I'll beautifully struggle.
互いの砂時計
As we look at our hourglasses,
眺めながらキスをしようよ
let's share a kiss.
「さよなら」から一番
Let's plan to meet somewhere
遠い 場所で待ち合わせよう
farthest from "goodbye".
ついに時はきた 昨日までとは序章の序章で
Finally, the time has come, everything up 'til yesterday was a prologue.
飛び出し読みでもいいから ここからが僕だよ
Skimming through is fine, from here on is my story.
経験と知識と カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
With experience, knowledge, and courage covered in mold,
いまだかつてないスピードで 君のもとへダイブを
at an unprecedented speed, I'll dive right into you.
まどろみの中で 生生しいコーラに
Dozing off into a lukewarm can of soda,
ここでないどこかを 夢見たよ
I dreamed of a world far from here.
教室の窓の外に 電車に揺られ 運ばれる朝に
Searching outside the classroom window, or on the morning train ride.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
Words like "tomorrow" or "future" or "fate", no matter how far they reach,
伸ばそうとも届かない 場所で僕ら恋をする
we fall in love in a place beyond reach.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
Even the clock's hands tick past us sideways,
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも 生き抜いていこう
let's live through such a world together, for a lifetime, no, across any number of chapters.
「はじめまして」なんてさ 遥か彼方へと追いやって
Putting "nice to meet you" far behind,
1000年周期を 一日で息しよう
breathing a thousand-year cycle in a single day.
辞書にある言葉で 出来上がった世界を憎んだ
Hating a world made purely of dictionary words,
万華鏡の中で 八月のある朝
inside a kaleidoscope on an August morning.
君は僕の前で ハニカムでわすまししてみせた
You appeared before me, acting shy yet composed,
この世界の教科書のような笑顔で
with a smile like the world's textbook.
嘘みたいな日々を 規格外の意味も
Days like a lie, and meanings beyond measure,
悲劇だっていいから 望んだよ
even wishing for tragedies if it brings the thrill.
そしてドアの外に 君が全部抱えて立っていたよ
And then you were standing outside the door holding everything.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
Words like "future" or "fate", no matter how far they reach,
伸ばそうとも届かない 場所で僕ら遊ぼうか
let's play together in a place beyond reach.
愛しささえも 君の匂いがした
Even the way you were loved carried your scent,
歩き方さえも その笑い声がした
even the way you walked carried your laughter.
いつか消えてなくなる 君のすべてを
All of you that will someday disappear,
この目に焼き付けておくことは もう権利なんかじゃない 義務だと思うんだ
burning it into my eyes is not just a right, but my duty.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
Words like "future" or "fate", no matter how far they reach,
伸ばそうとも届かない 場所で僕ら恋をする
we fall in love in a place beyond reach.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
Even the clock's hands tick past us sideways,
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも 生き抜いていこう
let's live through such a world together, for a lifetime, no, across any number of chapters.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
Words like "future" or "fate", no matter how far they reach,
伸ばそうとも届かない 場所で僕らの恋をする
we fall in love in a place beyond reach.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
Even the clock's hands tick past us sideways,
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも 生き抜いていこう
let's live through such a world together, for a lifetime, no, across any number of chapters.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
Even the clock's hands tick past us sideways,
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも 生き抜いていこう
let's live through such a world together, for a lifetime, no, across any number of chapters.
一生 いや、何章でも 生き抜いていこう
For a lifetime, no, across any number of chapters.
生き抜いていこう
Let's live through it.
カニさんなんて
Saying "Kani-san"!
今すごい重い
That's so heavy right now!
アチシがに？
"Atishi ga ni?"
私がに？何がに？私がに？って何？
"Atishi ga ni?" What is that?
アチシがに？って何？アチシがに？変じゃない？
"Atishi ga ni?" What does that mean? Isn't that weird?
え、今エモい！エモい言いながらエモい！
Eh, it's emotional right now! Saying it's emotional while being emotional!
え？
Eh?
ここ海！海！アチシがに？え？
This is the ocean! Ocean! "Atishi ga ni?" Eh?
アチシがに？アチシがに？
"Atishi ga ni?" "Atishi ga ni?"
え？アチシがに？アチシがに？いぇーい！イェーイ！
Eh? "Atishi ga ni?" "Atishi ga ni?" Yay! Yay!
あれ？なんか違うような、あれ？ほら。綺麗だな。新曲 綺麗だね。
Huh? That sounds a bit different, huh? Look. It's so pretty. The new song is pretty.
え、でもなんかちょっと違うよね？でもアチシがにの方が綺麗だよ。
Eh, but isn't it a bit different? But "Atishi ga ni" is prettier.
ちょっとどういうことさ？何してくれちゃってんのさ？アチシがになんて何さ？
Wait, what do you mean by that? What did you make happen? What is "Atishi ga ni"?
なんかそういう流れになっちゃってんじゃん。皆さんどうも！アチシがにー！新しい挨拶ができちゃってるよね、それ！
It just turned into that kind of flow. Hello everyone! "Atishi ga-ni!" A new greeting has been created, hasn't it!
このライブに来せ パーフェクトメイドの！アチシがにです！
The perfect maid who came to this live! I am "Atishi ga-ni"!
名前がアチシがにさんになってんだよ！おかしいんだよ！名前がね、アチシがにさんになっちゃって...アチシ、ガニ。
My name has become "Atishi ga-ni-san"! That's weird! My name became "Atishi ga-ni-san"... Atishi, Gani.
違う！違う！アチシガニです！違うよね、ガニさんじゃんそれ！
No! No! I am Atishi-Gani! That's wrong, you're Gani-san!
違うね！アチシガニなんよね？違う！違う！アチシガミョウジ...アチシがにが名前！
No! I'm Atishi-Gani, right? No! No! Atishi-myouji... Atishi-Gani is my name!
新しい人なんよね、それ！2期生って結構前からいらっしゃるけど、知らないよ、それ！
You're a new person, right! 2nd gen has been around for quite a while, but I don't know about that!
こんなキャラじゃないの！こんなキャラじゃないよ！あれ？皆さんどうも、こんくあーんって感じだよ！みんなたくあんですって！
This isn't my character! This isn't my character! Huh? Hello everyone, it's like "Konkuan"! Everyone is "Takuan"!
皆さんどうも！アチシがにー！カニカニカニって！
Hello everyone! "Atishi ga-ni!" Kani kani kani!
ご挨拶よ、新しいご挨拶！アチシがにいいカニカニカニって使うわ、これから。
It's a greeting, a new greeting! I'm gonna use "Atishi-ga-ni-ii kani kani kani" from now on.
私はたくあとアクアとして配信するから！アチシガニ、アチシガニ！新しい挨拶として...やだやだだ！
I'm streaming as Taku-Aqua! Atishi-Gani, Atishi-Gani! As a new greeting... No way, no way!
皆さんどうも！アチシがにー！カニカニカニ！
Hello everyone! "Atishi ga-ni!" Kani kani kani!
こんなの聞いてないよ
I didn't sign up for this!
おかしいんだよね、ねえ。おかしいよ、ちょっと。え？
This is weird, right? Hey. It's kind of weird. Eh?
でも今日から紫咲シオンでしょ？え、どうしよ、私。
But starting today I'm Murasaki Shion, right? Eh, what do I do?
こんばんは。紫咲シオンでちゅう。ちゅう。ちゅう。
Good evening. I'm Murasaki Shion-de-chuu. Chuu. Chuu.
ま、ま、まい…
Ma, ma, mai...
かわいい！
So cute!
シオンでちゅう。
It's Shion-de-chuu.
一勝負やんな？あくしがにしょ？
It's a showdown, right? Akushigani, right?
え？しがにやって！しがにはもうネタなんよ。
Eh? Shigani? Shigani is already old news.
私の体に何やってんのって感じなのよ。
It's like, what are you doing to my body?
がにまただし！あ、しがに！
Bow-legged! Ah, Shigani!
違う違う違う！動いて！ねえ、やばい！
No, no, no! Move! Hey, this is bad!
ねえ、本当にやばいって！
Hey, this is seriously bad!
今日からね、ちゅう、ちゅうね。ねずみ？
Starting today, chuu, chuu, right? Mouse?
あ、かわいい！ちょっと可愛すぎだよな、これ。
Ah, cute! This is almost too cute, isn't it?
あ、か、かに！シオンでちゅう、ちゅう、ちゅう！
Ah, ka, kani! Shion-de-chuu, chuu, chuu!
ねえ、やだ！やだ！
Hey, no way! No way!
え、こんなんじゃ…もっと可愛くして！可愛くして！
Eh, like this... Make me cuter! Make me cuter!
シオンでちゅう、ちゅう、ちゅう！へいらっしゃい！
Shion-de-chuu, chuu, chuu! Welcome!
それ違うよ！それダメなやつだから！ダメ！
That's wrong! That's a no-go! No!
それ違うやつ！それ違うやつ！へいらっしゃい！あっちがいにっちょ！
That's a different one! Welcome! Over to the other side!
がんばれ！シオンでちゅう！
Do your best! Shion-de-chuu!
ちょっとさ、そんなことよりさ、そんなことよりさ…どうすんのよ！
Wait, more importantly than that... What are we gonna do?!
本当だよ！どうすんのよ！このままみなとあくあとして生きてくしかなくなっちゃうよ！
Seriously! What do we do?! We'll have no choice but to live as Minato Aqua!
だめよ、それ。困るよ。
That's no good. That's a problem.
何が嫌なの？嫌だよ！
What do you hate about it? I hate it!
戻りたいもん！だってこの体が…
I want to go back! Because this body is...
やばい！やばい！だめだめだめ！カニアイドル！カニアイドルじゃないよ！
Yaba! Yaba! No no no! Crab idol! I'm not a crab idol!
カニ好きだけど！カニ回のプリンセス！違う違う違う！嫌なんよ！
I like crab though! Princess of Crab World! No no no! I hate it!
嫌なの！戻りたいの！普通にゲームしてたいの！
I hate it! I want to go back! I just want to play games normally!
どうやったら戻れんの？じゃあ掃除しなさい！
How do we get back? Then go clean up!
え？私、魔法使いだから掃除しないよ！
Eh? I'm a wizard so I won't clean!
じゃ、ご飯作りなさいよ！え？私なんか立場がちょっと…
Then make dinner! Eh? My status is a bit...
あんた、メイドでしょ？ちがっ、私メイドなんじゃないよ、今は！
Ah, you're a maid, right? No! I'm not a maid right now!
今は違うの。そうか。じゃ、どうやったら戻れるの？
Right now is different. Is that so. Then how can we go back?
教えてあげるよ。教えて？魔法。魔法？君なら使えるよ。
Shall I teach you? Tell me? Magic. Magic? You can use it.
確かに…魔法使いの格好してるけど、無理だよ！君、習ってないもん！
True... You're dressed like a wizard, but it's impossible! You haven't learned it!
じゃあ、教えてあげるよ。急にさ、車の運転してくださって言っても運転できないじゃん。
Then, I'll teach you. If I suddenly tell you to drive a car, you can't drive, right?
はい、指出して！はい、指出してください、はい！
Yes, stick out your finger! Yes, stick out your finger, please!
紫おちゃまビーム！
Murasaki-ochama Beam!
行くよ、じゃあ。紫おちゃまビーム！
Here we go, then. Murasaki-ochama Beam!
そんなんで戻れるわけねえだろ！え、なんで？
There's no way you can go back with that! Eh, why?
え、いますごい可愛かったんだけど！
Eh, that was super cute just now!
え、どうしたらいいの？しょうがないな、お手本見せてあげるよ。
Eh, what should I do? It can't be helped, I'll show you an example.
紫おちゃまビーム！
Murasaki-ochama Beam!
ええっ、これでいいの？
Ehh, is this good?!
あの日見渡した渚を
I still remember the shore
今も思い出すんだ
we looked out at that day...
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words we wrote in the sand, and the sight of you from behind
寄り添う波が足元を よぎり何かをさらう
The clinging waves brush past our feet, washing something away
夕凪の中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎていく
In the evening calm, only twilight passes us by
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched fireworks blooming in a flash of light
きっとまだ終わらない夏が 曖昧な心を溶かして繋いだ
Surely this summer is far from over, melting and tying our uncertain hearts
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
あと何度君と同じ 花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can watch the same fireworks as you
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
What can I do for that smiling face?
傷つくこと喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と感情 焦燥 最終列車の音
Getting hurt, feeling happy, repetitive waves and emotions, impatience, the sound of the last train
言葉にして
Putting it into words,
君を呼ぶよ
I call out to you.
波間を選び もう一度
Choosing the waves, once again.
もう二度と 悲しまずに済むように
So I won't ever be sad again.
はっと息をのめば
Fading with a gasp,
消えちゃいそうな光が
the light that seemed to disappear
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
surely lived on in our hearts.
手を伸ばせば触れた
Reaching out, I touched
あったかい未来は
a warm future
どこかに二人を見ていた
that had secretly been watching us.
パっと花火が 夜に咲いた
With a bang, fireworks bloomed in the night,
夜に咲いた
bloomed in the night,
夜に咲いて 静かに消えた
bloomed in the night and quietly faded.
離れないで もう少しだけ
Don't let go yet, just a little longer,
もう少しだけ このままで
just a little longer, just like this.
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
The shore we looked out over that day, I still remember it now,
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
words engraved on the sand, your silhouette.
パっと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
Shining with a bang, we watched the fireworks,
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
surely summer wasn't over yet.
曖昧な心を 溶かして繋いだ この夜が続いて欲しかった
Unraveling and connecting our uncertain hearts, I wanted this night to last.
ラララ… ラララ…
La la la...
違うよ
That's wrong!
違う
Wrong.
え？
Eh?
これだと Yes、フォーリンラブになるに違うんだよね。
Like this it would be... 'Yes, falling in love', which is different.
違う、でも、うん、やりたいって言って…
No, but, yeah, you said you wanted to do it...
あ、あ、あ…
Ah, ah, ah...
あ、違ったよね？
Ah, that was wrong, right?
うん。
Yeah.
間違いなんでしょ、ちょっと。
You got it wrong, didn't you?
間違いって…ねえ、ちょっと。
What do you mean 'wrong'... hey, come on.
そんなもさあ、ねえ、いい、なんかエモい感じだったのに、なんでそんなことすんのって。
It was such a nice, emotional vibe, why'd you have to do that?
でも、やりたいって…
But you said you wanted to...
違う！
No!
そうじゃなくて、間違えちゃった！
That's not it, I just messed up!
あとということでね、えー、次が最後の曲になるんですけれども。
And with that, um, our next song will be the last one.
早いね。
That's fast.
早い！
So fast!
なんかきの流れは、ね、ちょっとYouTubeも狂っちゃったけどね。
The flow of time, you know, even messed up YouTube.
これ何、この手、上げちゃった。
What's with this hand, I raised it.
上げちゃった。上げとこ、上げとこ。
You raised it. Let's keep it down, keep it down.
ちょっとYouTubeもちょっと狂っちゃったけどね、最後の曲になります。というわけで、えー、
Even YouTube got a bit messed up, but this will be our final song. So, um,
その前に！
Before that!
何？
What?
すごい、あるでしょ、言うことが！
There's something amazing you need to say!
ん？ 何？
Hm? What?
すごい告知？
An amazing announcement?
すごいヤツよ。
A huge one.
言うも？
Say it?
いっちゃん？
First?
いや、言わないと！
No, you gotta say it!
そうだよね。
That's right.
すごいのは先に！
The amazing stuff first!
言っとかんと。
You have to say it.
そうだね。
True.
じゃあ、せーので、ばーって出るから。
Then on the count of three, it'll pop right up.
あ、いくよ？
Ah, ready?
いくよ？
Ready?
せーの！
One, two, three!
22時22分に！
At 22:22!
動画が！
A video...
あがるよー！
Will be released!
めぇへらじゃないもん！
Mehera Ja Nai Mon!
ピンク！
Pink!
ということで、えーと、このあと22時22分に、えっとプレミアム公開で、え、私の、え、あくあチャンネルのYouTubeで、えっと、「めぇへらじゃないもん」歌ってみたの、え、動画が上がります！
And so, right after this at 22:22, a premiere of my cover video for 'Mehera Ja Nai Mon' will be uploaded on Aqua Channel on YouTube!
イェーイ！
Yay!
というわけで、めっちゃかわいいね、イラスト！めっちゃかわいいの、これ！
So, the illustration is super cute! It's so adorable!
ちなみにね、MP3もめっちゃかわいい
By the way, the MP3 is super cute too.
見ろ？
Look...
見たよ。
I saw it.
知ってるよ。
I know.
そうそう、あなた知ってるってどうするの？って話よね。確かにお願いしまーす。
Right? So if you know, what should we do?
でね、よかったらみんなね、
So, everyone, if you'd like,
このあと見ててね、
after this...
そう、プレミアム公開に私たちもね、コメントするから
We'll be commenting on the Premium broadcast too,
よかったら一緒に見てください！お願いします！
so please watch it together! Please!
めちゃめちゃ可愛いよね？しおんのも、もう可愛い。
It's super cute, right? Shion's is super cute.
もう可愛い！もう可愛いよ！
It's so cute! So cute!
ツインテールで、
With twin tails.
えー、そしてね、
And then...
うん、これがすごい告知。
Now, this is a big announcement.
すごいやつね、絶対みんな見なきゃダメなやつ。
A super big one! Absolutely can't miss it!
わかった、みんな？
Got it, everyone?
みんなわかった？
Does everyone get it?
見てね！
Watch it!
見れって言ってるよ、見れって！
They're saying watch it!
私たちもちゃんとコメントしようね？
We'll make sure to comment too, okay?
「可愛い！」って。
Saying "So cute!"
「私可愛い！」って。
"Mine is cute!"
「私の画が可愛い！」
"No, mine is cute!"
「私のが可愛い！」
え、しおん知らないんでしょ？
Shion doesn't know!
あくあ来るの知らないんでしょ？
Aqua doesn't know!
しおっこん見て！
Shio-con, look!
やだ、やだー！
No way!
だめ！
だめなんだから、本当にもう！
No way, so...
すぐコメント売ってよ！
Quick, comment on it!
えー！？
Eh?!
ねえ、ちゃんとしろよ、本当に。
Hey, you've gotta read it properly.
すごい告知の次は？
The next announcement is...
はい、だね。えっと、
Yes! So, um...
ま、これはね、もう告知されているんだけども、
Well, this has already been announced,
ま、くしょライブということで、もう一回告知しときましょうか。
as a Shio Live, let's announce it one more time.
そうですね。
That's right.
だ、だからね、うん。
That's right, yeah.
えー、私たち、なんとですね、ま、2期生、えっと、3周年になりました、最近。
So, um, it's already the 3rd anniversary for the 2nd generation!
そうだよ。
That's right!
みんな3周年だったね、ということで。
Everyone, it's been 3 years!
そう、そうだから、えっと、3周年の、え、記念グッズが、え、発売になりました！
So, um, the 3rd anniversary commemorative merchandise has been released!
え、じゃあ私から行きましょう。
So let's start with me!
え、3つあります、全部で。1つ目の告知こちら！
There are three things in total. Here's the first announcement!
ででーん！
Tada!
3周年記念グッズがただいま発売中です、やったー！わーい！
The 3rd anniversary commemorative merchandise is now on sale! Yay!
いえーい！
Yay!
え、9月の、え、13日まで発売されておりますー！
It will be available until September 13th!
というわけでね、ええと、この中には
So, um, inside this...
はい、ちょっと、触って、触って！ねえ、触って！
Hey, wait. Touch it, touch it!
この中には？はい、この中には何が？
What's inside this?
えっと、記念さ、え、活動3周年記念の、え、フルセット、えっと、記念グッズ3種と、ボイスが1種、入っておりますー！
It includes the 3rd anniversary commemorative goods (three types) and one voice track!
はい。
Yes.
で、えっと、ま、3周年を記念した高級感のある、え、A4の複製原画が、イラスト、トモセシュンサク先生が描き下ろしてくれてます！ちょっと、じゃまーよ！
And, um, to celebrate the 3rd anniversary, Tomose Shunsaku-sensei has drawn a luxury A4 reproduction illustration for us! How awesome is that?
じゃまーよ！
How annoying!
そして、それ以外にも、え、アクキャット.Tシャツ！
And besides that, there's also the Aquacat.T-shirt!
可愛いでしょう、これ！にゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃ。
Isn't this cute? Nya, nya, nya...
可愛い！
So cute!
あと、え、アクキャット.dotキーホルダーもあります！
And there is also the Aquacat.dot keyholder!
こちらは、え、カセ先生が描いてくださいました！可愛い！
This was also drawn by Kase-sensei! So cute!
可愛い、にゃん！
So cute, nya!
え、そして残り、え、シチュエーションボイスもなんと今回は出しております。聞かなくていいです、これは。
And finally, we also have a situation voice this time! You don't have to listen to it, though.
えっ！？
Eh?!
聞かなくていいです！聞きたい！聞くのは、わし！
You don't have to listen to it! You wanna listen, right?
はい！
Yes!
ということで、告知2つ目は、こちら！
So that's the first announcement!
ちょ、邪魔だよ。お、邪魔だよ。
You're in the way!
こちら！え、みなとあくあ、超BIGぬいぐるみが、復刻版として発売されました！いえーい！
Minato Aqua's Super BIG Plushie has been released as a comeback version! Yay!
こちらも期間限定なので、
This is also a limited-time offer,
よかったらみんな、みんな買ってね！13日まで買えます。
so everyone, please buy it! Until September 13th!
しおんちゃん、これ買ったの？
Shion, did you buy this?
これね、まだね、袋に詰まってるよ。あけなさい！
This, you know, is still in the bag, unopened. Open it!
あけろよ！あけろよ、あけて家族に見せろってよ！
Open it! Open it up and let the family see it!
はい、ということで、そちら概要欄から買えるのでチェックしてね！ねえねえ、よろしくお願いします！
So please check it out via the link in the description! Please!
そして3つ目は、こちら、どどん！
And the third one is... Tada!
あ、やっと、やっと2人、あ、やっと新曲、「海想列車」のダウンロード&ストリーミング配信が始まっておりまーす！
Ah, finally, finally... The download and streaming release of the new song "Kaisou Ressha" has started!
こちらね、YouTubeでもMVが投稿されてるので、ぜひね、今日は歌わなかったんですけれども、ぜひたくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
This, you know, the MV is also posted on YouTube, so although we didn't sing it today, we'd be super happy if you'd listen to it a lot! Please!
じゃあ次しおんちゃん行こっか。
So next, Shion-chan, let's go.
はい。
Yes.
海想列車…
"Kaisou Ressha"...
って、そんな曲じゃ、海想列車、ほんの少し…
Wait, that's not the song!
あ、え、違うよね？違うよね？
Wait, that's different!
違うよね？
That's not it!
ちょっと、テンションなくなっちゃった。
Wait, your tension is gone!
はい、ということでですね、
So, with that being said,
えー、しおんもですね、あの3周年の記念配信をしたときに発表したんですが、え、3周年記念グッズが発売中です！いえーい、どん！
Shion also announced her 3rd anniversary commemorative stream earlier, but the 3rd anniversary commemorative goods are now on sale! Yay!
じゃーん！
Tada!
こちら、たむゆ先生がね、描き下ろしで書いてくれました！ちょっと、まだ映ってないからな、それ。
So, Tamuyu-sensei drew and wrote this for us! Wait, it's not showing yet, is it?
あ、ちょっと、ちょっと、あ、ちょっと。ね、ちょっと。たむゆ先生のね、描き下ろしイラストの、え、ブランケットとね、これですね、これ。
Wait, Tamuyu-sensei's drawn illustration...
え、目覚まし時計、紫咲シオンのボイス入り目覚まし時計、
And the... Super BIG Plushie? No, it's the voice-included alarm clock!
これもたむゆ先生デザインのですね、え、ボイスがシオンのボイスがですね、56種類入った、え、収録、56種類だよ！56種類録音したボイスでシオンの声で起きれっていう、素晴らしい目覚まし時計となっております。
This is also designed by Tamuyu-sensei, and it has Shion's voice recorded 56 times, so you can wake up to Shion's voice—it's a wonderful alarm clock!
え、そしてですね、ランダムアクリルキーホルダーが1種。そう、全4種類のうちの1種がですね、記念フルセットではついてきます。
And the random acrylic keyholder is—one of them, yes, one of the four types comes with the commemorative full set!
いえーい！
Yay!
全部集めたい方はですね、あのたくさん買ってね！
If you want to collect all of them, well, you should buy a lot!
あ、いかがでしょうか？ イエーイ！
Ah, how is it? Yay!
そう、あと特典でポストカード、複製サインメッセージ入りのポストカードがついてきまーす！
Also, as a bonus, you'll get a postcard
with a printed signature and message!
はーい！
Yay!
イエーイ、よかったらよろしくお願いします。概要欄にあるのかな？
Yay, please check it out if you'd like.
Is it in the description box?
よろしくねー！
Please look forward to it!
そして次！紫咲シオン初オリジナル曲「メイジオブバイオレット」ドーン！
And next! Murasaki Shion's first
original song, "Major of Violet", boom!
わあー！イエーイ！
Wow! Yay!
はい、こちらのね、3周年の記念配信の後に、え、出させていただいたんですが、え、今日もですね歌いました「メイジオブバイオレット」。
Right, we released this after the 3rd-anniversary
stream, and we sang "Major of Violet" today.
MVの方の紫咲シオンチャンネルのYouTubeに公開されてるのと、あと
The MV is published on Murasaki Shion's
YouTube channel, and also...
ダウンロード配信ね？
Download and streaming, right?
ストリーミング配信みたいなものなので、そちらもですね、あの
It's like a streaming release,
so we'd be happy if you could...
「体操列車」と一緒に、よろしくお願いします。
listen to it together with "Taisou Ressha"!
「体操列車」と一緒に歌ったよね？ あ、いいじゃん！いいね！ 「体操列車」歌ったよねってことだ。
You sang "Taisou Ressha" together, right?
Ah, nice! Sounds good!
「歌ったよね」ってこと。
You mean "We sang it together."
お願いしますー！
Please check it out!
Please!
と言うことで、はい、最後の曲に行きましょうかかね。
So, um, shall we move on
to the final song?
行きましょう！
Let's go!
そろそろあくシオちゃんもね、そう、もうね、そう、あくシオちゃんもそろそろね、やっぱ、もう時間だし戻らなきゃいけないから、あくシオ性に。
It's almost time for Aqua and Shion to head back...
Since you came from Aqua-Shio-sei.
あくシオ性から来たんだ。そうそうそうそう。
You came from planet Aqua-Shio.
That's right, exactly.
あくシオちゃんもそう。
Shion-chan too, right?
このあとカニ鍋食べてあくシオ性に帰るから。
After this, we're gonna eat crab hot pot
and return to planet Aqua-Shio.
皆とお別れの時間、そろそろ。
It's almost time to say goodbye to everyone.
そうだよ、寂しいな。
That's right, how lonely.
しおんたんの時ハートの目。
Shion-tan has heart eyes right now.
え、なんでやねん、おかし、でもハートにしたい。
Eh, why? Weird,
but I want heart eyes.
ハートは？
Hearts?
と言うことでね、え、最後の曲はですね、まあ、歌ってみたでもね、こちらは動画を上げてる、あの曲、
And so, um, the final song is, well, a song
we've also posted a cover video of, that...
あの、有名なね、あれを、そうです。
that famous one, yes. We sing it, but...
歌うだけれども、
We sing it, but...
やっぱりさ、あの人呼んじゃわないと、だめだと思うんだよね。
Still, you know, if we don't call
THAT person, it won't work, right?
始まんないよね、やっぱり。
It wouldn't start, right?
そうそうそうそう、いないと。
Exactly, if he's not here.
あのね、やっぱホロライブの、大きな、もうこのなんて言うんだろうね、トップと、監督のある、監督のある笑顔がよく似合うね、
You know, hololive's big... what should I call it,
top... the director with that smiling face...
こういうやつね、こういうやつ。どういう、あ、そう
A guy like this, a guy like this.
What kind of... ah, right.
そういうやつね、こうい...
A guy like this, lik...
みなみん、これよ。みな、こういうやつ。こういうやつ。
Minamin, this one. Mina,
this kind of guy. This kind of guy.
ちっちゃいのがいれば、呼ばないとね？ 呼ばないと！
If there's a small one, we gotta call him,
right? Gotta call him!
やっぱり。と言うことでね、よかったらコメントで、え、コールしてくれると嬉しいです。
Indeed. So, we'd be happy if you
could call him out in the comments.
それじゃあ、呼ぶよ、みんなせーの、ヤーゴー！
Well then, let's call him!
Everyone, ready, set, YAGOO!
ヤーゴー！はい！ヤーゴー！はい！ヤーゴー！はい！ヤーゴー！はい！ヤーゴー！
YAGOO! Yes! YAGOO! Yes!
YAGOO! Yes! YAGOO! Yes! YAGOO!
来るか、どこから来る？ 上から？下から？右から？左から？ どこだ？ 下から！
Is he coming? Where's he coming from?
From above? Below? Right? Left? Where? From below!
ヤーゴーさん！
YAGOO-san!
どうもこんにちは。
Hello there.
と言うことで、え、今回は、え、ヤーゴーと一緒に、DJヤーゴーが、DJヤーゴーが、え、バックにいて、歌っていきたいと思います！
So, um, this time, along with YAGOO,
DJ YAGOO is backing us up, and we're going to sing!
準備はいい？
Are you ready?
うん！ 金のなさい！
Yeah! Listen up!
せーの、おことば戦争！
Ready, set, Okochama Sensou!
昔々のそのまた昔 とある貴族の仲良しな兄弟
Once upon a time, yes, a very long time ago
Lived a family noble and old whose children were very close
「ちゃんときれ！」
"Hey, do it right!"
じいヤが呼ぶ 席につけ よーいどん！
Now to your throne, the butler starts the show
Ready, go!
ナイフとフォークで応戦いたしますの
A knife and a fork to point in your face
I'll take you any day!
だって僕らはブルジョアの
After all we're noble
立派な立派な貴族様なすですの
The middle class's grandest and richest family
ひれ伏せ愚民 君との違いを
So don't ever look down on us!
So bow down to us, you peasants!
ヴァイヴァイサイロ 見せてやるぜ
Standing here's your prince and princess
We're here to call to attention your mistakes--
おい まてまて また勝手にそんな 見切れるような ハッタリかまして
Hey, hold up! Aren't you lying again?
What do you bet you can't see through what I throw?
はーい はい はい お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
Right, right, right, I'll leave them under you,
Since you want it so bad! (giggle)
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
You're just so annoying!
God, just so annoying!
兄に対して生意気な態度 喧噪の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Acting high and mighty around me like you're the queen
Ready aim and fire! Gong that never tires!
ケンカ勃発で宣戦布告 悪ふざけして 悪ノリして
Rioting tonight, it's a war but not a fistfight
Causing so much trouble, see my mischief double
ほらほら煽っていくStyleで “大安売り”買っちゃったら
C'mon boy, you gotta admit that I do it in style!
And for buying at this "Special bargain sale"
毎回ありがとう君の負け！（しゃー！）
I thank you for your precious service,
Beat you fair and square! (hya!)
つたない引き出しと 煽り合いの駆け引きで決める兄の威厳 見せるため 雨と鞭
Back to backing away, retreat, but I have an idea to beat
Giving into her puri elle goals, we're head to head
Hibana chiru chiru 両者の目と目 俺を誰だと思ってん
"Who the hell do you think I am?"
Yeah, I'm the rulebook, that's a slam!
くらえ！俺様がルールブック▼ へたれじゃない ひよってない
Calling me so dumb, thinking that I'll run
Maybe humility's not so bad, now now, everyone
ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ さぁさぁ皆さん お手を拝借
Come and take my hands please,
It's only natural that I'm tranquil
当たり前だろ 優勝確実 生まれながらにして地位と
If you really didn't know, I cheat by nature,
Always looking for that one thing greater
やべ キラメキ人生がスタート
It's in my blood! You know we're famous
For! Our! War! Strength!
当然です 見てみな優勝は
This one there, that one there, everywhere!
はい論破 はい論破 はい論破
Yes, I've won the fight! Peace sign!
Yay! (v * - * ) /
もらってくぜ Vサイン yay！( ｖ＾－ﾟ)♪
Guess who earned a gold star for
"Very good job!" (laugh)
はーい はい はい
You're just so annoying!
God, just so annoying!
はなまる よくできました☆
Acting high and mighty around me like you're the king
I'll strike even harder, shoot you 'til you topple
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Retribution! Punishment!
I'll make you feel all of it
僕に向かってへらず口なんだから
Looking down upon you, seeing through all your moves
Chance is for the taking, you're dancing to my beat!
とっておきを君に魅せよう
Got a little messy, missed you by a hair
Oh well! It looks like I'm the winner, beat you!
復讐！制裁！挑発しちゃって
(yes!)
意地悪して 一枚上手 チャンスはもらえるスタンスで 痛恨ミス！あっちちっち
You're the only rival that I can bear
Sei! Yaa! Too! Yaa! U! Too! Yaa! Ha!
おあいにく様だね君の負け！YES！
Falling to my knees, losing like I'm weak
Would drive me insane, so for tonight it's you and me
むかしむかし そのまたむかし
Once upon a time, a long, long time ago
とある貴族の 仲良し兄弟
Lived a noble family's close siblings
（ちゃんとやれ!）
(Do it right!)
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ よーいどん!
The butler calls, take your seats, ready, go!
ナイフとフォークで 応戦いたしますの
Replying with a knife and a fork
だって僕らは ブルジョアの
Because we are the bourgeoisie's
立派な 立派な 貴族様なんですの
Splendid, splendid noble lords indeed
はれふせ愚民 君との違いを
Bow down, peasants, showing you the difference
ヴアイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
Viceroy, I'll show you
おい まてまて また勝手にそんな
Hey, wait, wait, doing as you please again
見切れような ハッキリかまして
Making such a bold display
はーい はーい はい はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes
お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
As big brother commands (lol)
ざーむむかづくぜ まーじむかづくぜ
Damn it, seriously pissing me off!
兄に対して 生意気な態度
Showing such impudent attitude to your brother
闇の声ボングを鳴らせ
Sound the bong of voices in the dark
ケンカ勃発で 宣戦布告
Declare war with a sudden fight!
だけど君 君だけが
But it's you, and only you
僕に二人のライバル
The two rivals I have
落ちるのも へこんでんのも
Falling down or feeling depressed
調子狂わされるから
Will throw off my groove
今宵もあんたと やいやいやいやいや
So tonight with you too, yeah yeah yeah
ざーむむかづくぜ まーじむかづくぜ
Damn it, seriously pissing me off!
僕に向かって へらずぐちなんざ
Talking back to me like that
とって置きを君に見せまえ
I'll show you my best trick
復讐! 制裁! 挑発しちゃって
Retribution! Punishment! Provoking me
いじわるして いちまいうえ
Being mean and staying one step ahead
チャンスはもらって スタンスで
Taking the chance in my own stance
痛恨ミス! あっちゃっちゃあ
Critical miss! Oops!
おあいこさまだね 君の負け!
We're even now, your loss!
つたない引き出しと 誘いあいの駆け引きで
With clumsy drawers and enticing negotiation
決める 兄の威厳見せるため アメとアメ
To show my brotherly dignity, candy and candy
ヒビカバ散る散る 両者の目と目
Sparks flying between our eyes
俺を誰だと思っている
Who the hell do you think I am?
くらえ! 俺様がルールブック
Take this! I am the rulebook
当然だろ 余裕綽々
Of course, totally calm and collected
はい論破 はい論破 はい論破!
Argument destroyed, argument destroyed!
ざーむむかづくぜ まーじむかづくぜ
Damn it, seriously pissing me off!
にぐまれいごしはお口をチャック
Zip it, you hateful mouth
闇の声ボングを鳴らせ
Sound the bong of voices in the dark
次世代エンペラーは この僕だ!
The next-generation emperor is me!
悪戯して 悪ノリして
Causing mischief, riding along with it
ほらほら 煽ってくStyleで
Look, look, with a provoking style
1から100いただきます
I'll take everything from 1 to 100
毎度ありがとうで 君のま…
Thank you as always for your...
まさかの日、引き分け!?
Wait, is this a draw!?
だけど君 君だけが
But it's you, and only you
僕に二人のライバル
The two rivals I have
落ちるのも へこんでんのも
Falling down or feeling depressed
調子狂わされるから
Will throw off my groove
今宵もあんたと やいやいやいやいや
So tonight with you too, yeah yeah yeah